hello I'm your host David Barnard and my
guest today is Hannah parvas founder of
aperture a full service growth partner
making good companies better with more
than a decade of experience in the app
industry Hannah has mentored and helped
grow hundreds of companies on the
podcast I talk with Hannah about how to
profitably scale Performance Marketing
hard versus soft activation and why you
should keep an extra close eye on your
marketing spend in
November hey Hannah thanks so much for
joining me on the podcast today hi it's
so nice to be on here thank you for
having me well you are one of the most
requested guest I've had several people
say we need to get Hannah on and I think
the reason is and I've talked about this
with Thomas petite that when you work
with a lot of different companies over
time you just build a lot of experience
and get to see a lot of things that the
average person who just works with one
app for most of their career or for the
last five years or whatever they just
don't don't get the variety of
experience that somebody like you get
working with so many different companies
so yeah I'm excited to really share some
of those learnings that you've had
working with so many different companies
over the years how did you get into
growth Consulting and product and all
these things you do in order to end up
working with so many companies over time
well it was never my plan you know I
didn't growing up I was like a
six-year-old going I'm going to be a
lawyer and then all of a sudden I found
myself in a little basement working with
a Lo of people people on a little app
was kind of a bit shocking but it it
started with me being in the music
industry so I was in the music industry
and live music artist management record
labels and so on and then I got into
music tech and joined a music app and
then the rest is history but for me I'm
someone that always has been very much a
multitasker you know so I learned by
being challenged and that's something
that's always been the case I was just
thinking of this quote that I was
talking about last week which is growth
and comfort do not coexist which jeie
retti who was the CEO of IBM said but I
just always wanted to find more
challenges and I felt like always I was
kind of learning by doing so about
201617 I started doing a lot of bits on
the side coaching mentoring and I think
that started when I went through 500
startups for the most part so I learned
a lot and I met a lot of really
interesting people and then soon after
that I got asked to Mentor for Google
and then one thing led to another I
started doing growth mentor which is
this fantastic platform for mentoring
Founders or seite or anyone really who
needs kind of support and I just caught
the bug juggling lots of walls and then
how did that turn into aperture in the
last I think 18 months or so you founded
an app agency a growth partner that you
now hired a bunch of people and you're
working with a lot of companies how did
you transition from that app to like
mentoring and side hustles to running
your own agency yeah I was a year old
last week actually so really I know
happy birthday after for show after I
left my last full-time in-house gig
which I was at for a year amazing
company we got some incredible results
of course i' been working with a fair
few products on the side and doing
freelancing with them or running their
ads on the side or doing consulting and
product strategy with them and it just
felt like the immediate and organic next
step like oh well I may as well
formalize this I'm loving so much
working on all of these separate
challenges and separate projects so why
don't I just do that full-time and then
it just kind of snowball and snowball so
I was working on it on my own pretty
much until January when we brought in
our first team member and now we're six
since January so that's really awesome
and we're still growing so it's amazing
aperture has been a fantastic year you
know even before aperture like you said
you've been working with so many
different companies and worked on app
growth yourself and that's what we
wanted to talk about today I hear from a
lot of folks who start dipping their
toes in marketing and see some potential
there run a few Facebook ads do some app
store search ads whatever those kind of
First Steps look like for them but then
scaling is where it really starts
getting challenging I know that's
something you spend a lot of time
thinking about so what would you say is
the first step in scaling Performance
Marketing whenever we're thinking about
scaling for Performance Marketing let's
say we have to have some Targets in
place that's the very first thing I
think about how are we actually
measuring what we're scaling so let's
say we're going to be starting working
with a new app the very first thing
we'll always do is start running app
install campaigns first of all so very
top of funnel get people to download
figure out what messages are working
what creatives are working with that so
that people can start to come through
the algorithms can start to learn we can
start to learn as well like our human
intelligence can start to learn which
kind of things are performing well and
then as we go further and we're able to
spend more and more we start moving
farther down the funnel so from install
to sign up from sign up to trial and
then to some custom events and as we
start to unlock more budget by bringing
back more money into that with our
subscription product we're able to get
better results especially since the kind
of iOS changes which we're all very
familiar with I'm sure you need to have
a bit of a different strategy you know
you have to get a certain number of
installs per day to see post install
events so you need to be spending at a
certain level to be ble to optimize for
that and so on so the very first thing
I'd be looking for is what are my
targets what are my optimization events
I'm aiming for if I'm already optimizing
for trial is there something else that
can be a custom event like trial and two
content views or trial and something
that we can start looking at that will
be a really clear indicator for success
and for someone going on to purchase and
succeed I actually recently downloaded
Jo lingo I mentioned to you before and I
actually got my ATT popup after I'd
completed like a few lessons and I was
like that's really interesting that
they're giving me an ATT popup at this
point like you don't care about anything
before that then okay I see I see you
know I turned off the ability for apps
to even ask I had thought about that
kind of being in the industry I need to
allow apps to ask me so I can see it's
really fascinating stage yeah cuz we've
done a lot of testing around it of
course and we were originally going to
put the ATT popup at a place that we
thought oh this will interfere with sign
up or this will interfere with trial
fewer people will do those actions but
actually the place that it had the least
impact on anything including conversion
to paying including hard activation rate
was on first launch so as soon as
someone opens the app for the first time
putting it straight there and just
having them press and moving on from
there which was shocking but now we're
rolling out everywhere the dualingo
thing is interesting because in a way
it's those users who do finish that
second or third lesson that are the ones
you most want to find audiences like and
so maybe that's the kind of theory
behind that is like we don't care about
tracking the users who fall off before
that second lesson we care about
tracking the users who stick around yeah
that's fascinating but then it's also
fascinating that like on launch wasn't
most successful but speaking of tracking
that and you've talked already about
custom events that you might want to
feed back and like measuring success and
all that stuff what are your favorite
tools for actually measuring those
things and how do you set up those flows
to understand what is being successful
when should you ask is the ask deterring
from sign up and onboarding completion
and things like that what do you
actually use to do that firstly we'd be
thinking about what is our AB testing
tool and how we're doing our tests to
see how we're implementing that
infrastructure so we often build that
ourselves with our developers building
our own systems and then measure in
Firebase or measure in mix panel or
something something like that but there
are many other tools and actually tools
like mix pannel have their own AB
testing Solutions now which is really
cool to see that grow over the last few
years but then on top of that if we're
thinking about where are people coming
in from and so on and we're trying to
measure all the way up to the top I'm
usually using one of three mmps so I'm
usually using appsfire adjust or
singular and then tracking down into
exactly what people are doing how those
flows are working with different cohorts
as well interestingly you see very
different results not surpris
of course with different cohorts but
yeah and then we build funnels of course
so within any kind of Analytics tool if
you're using amplitude or mix panel or
something like that you can build
funnels so you can build like step
funnels so this many people signed up
this many people went through Journey a
or Journey B and then this is the
actions that happened afterwards so that
we can see what is the incremental
uplift of having or not having this
feature so really cool when I talk to
individual app operators or people
working in bigger apps it's like they
have one specific tool but working with
so many people I yeah you end up working
with all the tools so you have to rely
on like building out the principles and
the Frameworks and then just figuring
out how to actually make it work in any
individual tool so like the ATT prompt
you would set that up as just an AB test
whether it's Firebase or mix panel or
optimizely or in-house testing tool we
want to know when is the optimal place
to put in the ATT prompt and then just
run a bunch of tests and see how it
performs exactly yeah run you know ABC
tests they don't always need to be like
a Ab just a control in one option at a
time as long as you're getting enough
traffic through you can run your control
against a few different options and it's
something that we do in the product and
something we also do from an advertising
perspective we always like to have a
control with multiple options see which
ones are getting the best uplift and
then start optimizing around that
specific one we kind of started talking
about scaling at performance and dig R
into a lot of different things but
specifically on scaling how are you
experimenting with creatives and trying
different things these days especially
in the postat world what's working like
spray and prey and are you getting good
measurement and then what kind of volume
do you need to really understand what's
going on versus just low volume stuff
where you can't really understand what's
working and what's not I think whenever
we're working with companies we say that
we only really start with a minimum of
like 6K budget at the moment that's the
very very minimum based on what an
average cost per install would be and
this is only to optimize on installs
right from the very beginning and so the
reason I say that is because to optimize
any campaign or any adset you need to
get 50 conversions a week in your first
seven days of launching so that's your
first hurdle can I get my 50 conversions
in a week firstly so am I able to hit
that point so if you're going to get 50
conversions in a week divided by seven
you have to get seven per day so imagine
like to begin with a cost per install is
going to cost you around5 $5 whilst
you're getting started so that's what we
say is the minimum entry point that we
then try and come down from so that then
allows you for a few different test
variants and then one prospecting
campaign so the way that we're doing all
of our experiments really are having
tests with one control and then multiple
variants which are like one element
different from each of them so if we're
testing a messaging test we will have
the exact same design but with four
different messages on there against a
control which one of these messages will
be our control once we then find out
which message works best we'll take that
one message and put it into four
different concepts like four different
Design Concepts so that could be like a
SMS conversation an iMessage
conversation that could be like an iOS
notes fake conversation that could be a
ugc style that could be many other
different things with this one message
to see if does this message actually
hold up on its own in different formats
we then see which format works best and
start exploring that a bit more with
different iterations with messaging
iterations within that as well so this
is really how we get started and as
we're starting to scale we're repeating
this process over and over and over and
over and over again until we start
finding a lot of different Creative
Concepts that are working and we're
upgrading we're putting these into our
always on campaigns and then leaving
them and trying to touch them as little
as possible you know we're trying to
keep our hands off those ones and that's
half of the job trying to interfere too
much with those so that's really the
Baseline and as we start to see success
there and we're starting to see success
on the app install format optimizing
only for app installs then we would
think about okay now we've got this
portfolio of creatives that's working
now we're going to start optimizing for
something else so we would duplicate
that campaign and then optimize it for
registration optimize it for trial
optimize it for our custom event that we
spoke about earlier see which one of
those performs better are we even able
to get to the point where we're able to
optimize for post install events because
you need to be getting a certain amount
of installs per day then so you change
from 50 in a week to like 120 in a day
that you need to get for your one
campaign so it's a big step increase
there 50 in a week to 120 in a day so
when you're doing that you need to be
ready to increase your budgets
dramatically without knowing so we try
and do this very very gradually with a
lot of control with a lot of
experimentation and a lot of analysis
going into it because we need to make
sure that there this budget increas is
sustainable as well it's fine to put it
up for a test but can we sustain this
budget level because the way it works
with the skad network is you might have
this one campaign set up in meta and
it's just got one campaign ID in meta
but actually in the skad network it has
like 10 campaign IDs and so inside then
the skad network you need each of your
campaign IDs to get a certain amount of
installs to get the postbacks so then if
you are going even underneath that
average some of the postbacks backs will
be empty then you'll be starting to miss
data and so on so even though I'm saying
you know you have to reach 120 or so is
actually making sure that that is the
very very minimum to be able to get
postbacks so unless you're hitting that
you know you're not going to be seeing
data visibility and so that's when we're
starting to make sure that we're also
looking in our MMP in our mobile
measurement partner so in like appsfire
or adjust or singular or something like
this because at the moment with some of
our companies we're seeing 60%
visibility or so in Facebook in mattera
versus what we see in our MMP so we
actually look at that as our source of
Truth are we seeing the results that we
need to see in our MMP we're judging our
success there and then scaling based on
that too yeah how do you talk to your
customers about this scaling process so
early on I imagine especially with that
$6,000 a month I would imagine a lot of
that's pretty investigatory and are they
seeing a return on that or are you
expecting that to be an investment where
they're not seeing much of a return or
maybe a 50% return or something but the
idea is okay you're going to invest
you're going to get some of it back but
we're going to learn and we're going to
get closer and closer to that return on
ad spend that you're looking for how do
you frame that conversation and I guess
it's different for each app and
different apps have different levels of
success during this exploration phase
absolutely yeah I mean firstly every app
is different as you say like everyone
needs different levels of success but
also everyone has a slightly different
strategy so for some of our companies at
the moment we're they're completely free
products so we're not running on iOS
we're running on Android because we're
not trying to make money from our
customers it's completely fine to run on
Android and since we're still safe there
for the time being from sunbox we're
still running there we're getting our
learnings there because when you're
running on Android at the moment there
aren't these kind of rules that I've
just been me talking about like we have
for iOS so there isn't minimum number of
installs that you need to get a day you
still need to get 50 a week to optimize
if you're on meta or 10 per day if
you're on Google for example but you
don't have to get this 120 plus installs
per day so if you have a lower budget it
can actually be good to test on a
platform like that but when I'm thinking
about how are we talking to our partners
about this we definitely see a big part
of what we're doing as education so we
spend a lot of time going over and over
this with our partners and making sure
that they are as clued up as we are on
it because we want them to have a full
understanding when we're talking about
this stuff with them because we're all
very technical people for non-developers
for us it's really important for them to
have an understanding of skad network of
all of the idfa changes of what are the
rules around this so that then when
they're looking at the numbers they are
informed we want them to look at this
and say okay this number of Trials might
not be accurate in mattera because we
actually didn't get enough installs here
and so on so it's really important for
them to know as well it's their business
after all and when you do have a
subscription I mean that's what we
mainly Focus focus on here on the
subclub podcast and so there is some
element of hoping to get a return do you
see just like wildly different
performance and then what would you
advise on the lower performance so let's
say you start scaling up your install
ads so you're optimizing for install
because you don't have enough volume yet
to optimize for deeper funnel and you
spend that 6,000 that month and you make
3,000 or a couple thousand or something
do you immediately jump back into
product or do you look for ways to get
that cost down or other things well the
very first thing that I'd be looking at
is everything from a blended perspective
so did I get 3,000 from my paid or did I
get 3,000 overall so if I'm getting
3,000 overall from a blended perspective
I would be first looking at all of my
funnel steps so where are my biggest
areas for opportunity so this then goes
into product so first firstly I'd be
looking at everything from cpms to
clicks to how people are installing how
are people registering are people
actually opening after that install
actually are they registering are they
taking out the trial and then the trials
are paid conversion so I would have kind
of internal benchmarks of what these can
be what we should be aiming for here for
subscription apps with trials and so on
so then from there we would look at okay
which area is laying us down are our
cpms really high is our click-through
rate really low if that was the case or
even if our click to install was low I'd
be looking at our ads definitely where
can we improve here which ads are
letting us down has something started to
saturate are there any new directions
that we should be testing how are people
engaging on these ads and so on and if
everything's looking fine there then I
would be looking into the product so our
people whenever we're thinking about
installs we have this kind of true
install which is actually the number of
people that went to the App Store and
clicked install but then there is also
your first app open install right which
is what we track in our most of our
business intelligence tools or in our
analytics tools so actually I was
working with one product and we saw that
only 70% of people were doing the first
app open after the true install so we
were like okay this is interesting you
know obviously then we have to zoom out
is there something on the App Store page
is there something on the ads is
something on like how we're
communicating like what can we do here
to push people further should we be
retargeting people who've installed but
not opened and so on so there's a few
different things that you can do there
but then if people are actually opening
your app then I'd be looking at what's
our registration rate how are people
taking out the trial and going into the
product itself to see where are again
our areas for improvement where our
biggest opportunities and then focusing
there and actually that can mean
sometimes pausing your ads till you fix
problems it does seem like ultimately to
get to profitability as a subscription
app you need some paino you're solving
you need some core product Market fit
and so I guess that's kind of what
you're saying it's like if you start
scaling up your ads and it's just not
working at all then maybe the first
place to look is that core value prop
and that do you have some level of
product Market fit how do you think
about that and how would you measure
that and then how would you start
improving that so from a product
perspective I would be looking at how
people are performing in terms of when
they're coming in are they doing their
first meaningful action so that could be
a signup that could be some kind of
order every product will be different
but a first meaningful action showing
that they're interested in the product
and then we'll have a core action
imagine you're a Content product you've
got lots of different stories on there
so maybe a core action could be clicking
on a story and reading it or listening
to a song on Spotify or booking a night
on Airbnb or something like this so
that's your core action so there will be
this set number of core actions that
someone needs to do to go from being
soft activated so from being just
starting their activation Journey
they're still seeing what's what they
don't fully trust or they're not fully
having the product embedded in their
lives so we have to figure out how many
of these that we should be doing so
imagine I was working at One content
product and we knew that someone had to
listen to six stories to become hard
activated what we did then was we gave
everybody 10 free stories to make sure
that they would get to that point so you
don't just give six just in case some
people might be a bit more or less
because six is the average and the
average is never the truth so we gave
everyone 10 free stories and
then waited to see what happened
obviously we were offering a trial
before that but then we would see that
people who completed actually six
stories who hadn't taken out a trial
would then take out a trial and convert
2x better to paid from that trial than
people who hadn't for example so these
are the sort of things that we'd be
looking at we'd be looking at okay where
is this activation Point think about
that six stories how many times does
someone need to do that core action okay
how many people are getting to that core
action is 1% % of people getting to that
core action okay then something is
blocking them what can we do to remove
friction there so that probably isn't
going to be removing trial from your
onboarding because we know that a lot of
these trial events come right in their
very first journey but after someone
dismisses the trial what are we doing to
make people move along that Journey how
are we making it simple are we doing
autoplay are we getting people to just
tap in are we doing tool tips are we
giving people rewards how are we
gamifying this initial experience even
if we're not a game you know to get
people to move along we'd be looking
really closely into that area how many
people are getting there but then also
looking at what are all of the steps
between that because let's say for the
six stories lots of people listen to one
but so getting people to listen to one
wasn't the problem it was getting people
to listen to the second one so how do we
get people to go onto that second one
and so on so this is what we'd be doing
I think a lot of subscription app folks
too often think of the trial start as
the core action but it's interesting how
you were so much more focused on that
core value prop is that they need to
interact with something that's going to
give them value starting a free trial is
not giving them value so whether they
start the free trial and listen to those
six stories or whether they listen to
the six stories and then start the free
trial the goal is to get them to listen
to those six stories so they're
experiencing the value that you're
delivering so then they stick around
through the free trial and that was an
interesting stat that in that case it
was 2x performance on the free trial by
getting them to listen to the stories
before they even start the free trial
that's fascinating absolutely I would
definitely caveat that with we tried
experimenting with moving the placement
of the trial and there's no way like we
would have removed it after the results
we saw from the initial onboarding right
cuz the number of people that go through
it on that initial onboarding even if
their counseling is so much higher than
waiting beyond that really so we always
give the opportunity to take out a trial
earlier on We Don't Force It it's not
like a hard hard cell the whole way
through but we give the opportunity for
trial and then give them more
opportunities later after they're a bit
warmer once you've gotten folks
experiencing that core value and started
to understand some level of product
Market fit and moving forward with
people getting value out of the app how
do you then track your Roi and build
Financial models around this to actually
then profit ably do it because there's
one thing to connect people with the
value we're all in this to make money to
a certain extent I mean even if there's
greater purpose in the app you you can't
spend $100,000 on ads and make 20 and
continue doing that so yeah how do you
build out the ROI and the financial
models to actually figure out what's
going to work whenever you're starting
and you're an early product a lot of
what you're going to be doing is just
finger in the air until you start
getting your initial results in firstly
so you're going to be looking at what
are the industry benchmarks you're going
to be looking at actually in app store
connect now you can see what are the
benchmarks in your industry which is
really cool to see so I'd be looking at
those if I'm just building my product
right from the very beginning so here
are my benchmarks these are what my
expected results will be and then I
start seeing what the truth
is and when we start seeing what the
truth is then we go and we start
adjusting and this is also how we
prioritize the areas that we need to
focus on because we might be seeing that
there's this big drop from install to
sign up and by having a slight increase
here we will have a much bigger increase
in our bottom of funnel events than
something that's a bit further down the
funnel if we increase our clicked
install by one percentage point that
will then have a much larger trickle
down effect in the later stage funnel
than increasing something like trial to
paid or something like that because
there's going to be so many more people
coming in right at the top of the funnel
right so that's something to bear in
mind but when we're thinking about how
our hard active motivation rates and so
on are factoring into our larger
Financial models people who are hard
active and the people who are reaching
you know let's say these six tracks or
continuing on from that the reason that
we are talking about this hard
activation rate is that people who get
to the six have a much lower drop off so
people who get to six like 98% of people
who listen to six listen to seven 98% of
people who listen to seven listen to
eight and it was like this very small
drop offs from event to event and so
people who are actually active are going
to stick around much much longer you
know people who are staying around and
when we're thinking about activation
everyone has an average there is always
this average I worked with one other
product where people would go to a bar
and then they'd get a free drink that
was how the app worked that was it and
it was an average of 21 days between
someone going to the bar okay but you
David might go to the bar every 35 days
and I might go every 18 days so so for
me if I haven't been to the bar until my
19th day if I haven't been on day 19
I've started to turn so everyone has
their own individual life cycle
frequency life cycle and for you if you
haven't been on day 29 you're still
active because your average is 35 days
so when we're thinking about this this
is how our hard activation pool grows
we're wanting to obviously grow the
number of people who are becoming soft
activated so the number of installs the
number of true Acquisitions that we're
getting but then we also want to grow
this hard activ a rate so how keeping
people active within their life cycle
within their kind of user frequency so
this is true of free products as much as
it is of subscription products and with
subscription products we're looking at
when we're thinking about having our
Northstar metric for example we want to
have obviously some kind of Revenue
Associated event in there so our
Northstar metric wouldn't just be
Revenue but it would be something like
weekly active subscribers because we
have a Cadence in there that someone is
coming and doing this event that they're
coming back and doing it weekly or maybe
it's monthly or maybe it's daily or
maybe it's fortnightly every two weeks
so Cadence action Revenue Cadence action
Revenue so weekly active or this could
be listening or this could be reading or
this could be something like this and
then subscribers so that you've got this
Revenue event in there so the reason
that we do this is so that we're
representing our customers as well as
ourselves in our company success in our
perceived Company Success then once we
have got all of our Northstar metric and
all of our metrics in place and we know
exactly how we're measuring success then
we start thinking about our Roi our roas
what is our lifetime value of the people
that are coming in so everything that
we're always doing should be with these
things in mind and this is why you know
when we're thinking about what are the
areas for the biggest impact these are
the areas for the biggest impact on our
Northstar metric and therefore on our
revenue on our investment for the ads
that we're doing so for that we're going
to be looking at things again from a
blended perspective because your ads are
also going to have this Halo effect so
once you're running an ad you see my ad
David eventually maybe if you like the
product you're going to tell someone and
so even though that person didn't see
the ad you saw the ad and so they
actually came through the ad indirectly
so there's this halo effect that we get
by running ads or also another example
is you've seen an ad a few times and
then you've got some kind of message in
your head and then something happens
externally you saw an ad on Monday and
then the following Monday your friend
mentioned something and you're like oh
I've remembered this product okay then
you go to the App Store you search it so
there's this halo effect on your ads
which might not necessarily be tracked
so this is why it's very important to
look at things from a blended
perspective and when I say Blended this
means looking at the spend that you're
doing on all of your paid channels so
this is the way to start looking at this
so how much are you spending on meta how
much you spending on Tik Tok Google add
all of that together and then look at
how many people have done these kind of
actions overall so how many installs
have you got overall from every channel
including organic how many Tri did you
get overall from every channel including
organic and then how many of these
converted to paying so we take that
total sum of money that we've spent and
then divide it by the Blended actions
that we've got so total number of Trials
total number of purchases so that we can
see how these numbers are increasing
over time but how our costs are
decreasing of course so this will help
us measure our halo as well and look at
the impact on Blended how do you think
about optimizing that performance thing
because if you're looking at Blended are
you simultaneous VI ly still looking at
Tik Tok specifically in the MMP looking
at Facebook specifically and are you
running like incrementality testing
where okay let's spend less on Facebook
this week and see how it impacts all of
this the Blended numbers let's spend
more on Tik Tok this week and see how
those Blended numbers shift is that how
you're thinking about it absolutely yeah
so we start every channel in isolation
really so we're looking out one channel
at a time to begin with we wouldn't
launch five channels at once we would
launch one see how this performs get
baselines and then start introducing
other channels once we've started to
master one of them and we're getting
good results with one so we would then
with each of the channels as well with
meta with Tik Tok with Google with
Pinterest like you can use these as
direct response channels or you can use
these as awareness channels so we do do
incrementality testing with all of the
channels on our direct response level
and also on our brand awareness level
and we don't spend a lot on brand
awareness but what we do do is do
engagement campaigns so we look at
boosting some of the Instagram posts
boosting some of the Tik Tok posts and
the reason that we do this is because we
are getting such cheap cpms cost per
impressions for these so a direct
response ad I might be paying somewhere
between like 7 and $12 CPM maybe a bit
lower and for the same similar people to
see my awareness ad I'll be paying maybe
$1 to $2 for a th000 people to see them
so what we try and do is we hit people
with our awareness SI ad hit them with
like some of our boosts from our
Instagram or Facebook or Tik Tok get
them to see things a few times as well
and then we're hitting them also with
our direct response at the same time so
our more expensive Impressions but these
are the ones that are then converting
and getting the results so we are
looking at our spend holistically we're
grouping our awareness and our direct
response spend and looking at how our
overall costs from that perspective have
come down and then we're looking at it
on a channel by Channel basis and as we
start to see some channels costs going
up we're constantly rooting money to
other channels so at the moment with one
of our companies for example our meta
costs have gone up dramatically over the
summer but we're still more than 2x
profitable on Google so just funneling
money over there at the moment and then
at some point there is just a standard
variance throughout the year so we might
then end up putting some money back but
ideally what we're going to do is then
start reaching an equilibrium with that
company across lots of different
channels with spend so that we're not
just having eggs and one basket we don't
want to just have like 95% of budget in
one place and 5% somewhere it's good to
have like a big percentage everywhere so
that then if things are going up and
down on one channel at least everything
else is balancing out and this has been
performing pretty well yeah that's
interesting and you talked about
seasonality there I was just thinking as
we record it's early October this is
going to come out like mid October how
do you think about Black Friday the
Christmas bubble like it seems like
pretty much all advertising starts
getting more expensive from say like
Halloween through the maybe second week
of the year once all the New Year's
resolutions have been made and all the
fitness apps have gone through their
budget how do you think about that
seasonality do you sometimes pull back
how do you Wade through the more
expensive campaigns during that time
yeah it's an interesting one to think
about at this time of the year because
every year is the same I've been
advertising in for like 12 years now and
every year it's been the exact same
passion which is from literally November
1st until literally November
30th the performance is just terrible
and I tell all of our companies every
year even when I've been full-time in
house November will be very expensive we
should be thinking more about brand
awareness and just putting a bit more
budget into brand awareness in November
and then without a doubt everyone always
freaks out in November except me because
I know it's going to happen that um a
psychic but I'm just looking at data
that November oh costs are going up so
we should be putting more money into
these boosts or into awareness campaigns
where we're getting lots of Impressions
because we know we're not going to get
the sales that month because everyone's
really excited to buy their physical
presents physical gifts for themselves
physical gifts for their family members
Partners this is where Ecom explodes and
then literally November 30th the cost
start to go down again and this has
happened every single year and it's
crazy like December 1st will always be a
really good day for us
and December will continue and actually
when I've spoken to The Meta teams about
this they call this period and we call
this period Q5 um so like December 15th
until the beginning of January is like
Q5 for spend because especially from
December 15th this is around when the
post stops your less posting
opportunities so Ecom spending reduces
dramatically so it's a really good
opportunity around them for this digital
product advertising and then going into
New Year if your product can be
beneficial for people in any way you
know you go into this like new year
messaging see really great results there
if you can do a sale that's amazing with
Revenue cap you can Implement a sale in
your products you can even run these
through your website there's many
different ways and another thing to
leverage at that time of year too is
gifting which a lot of people make a lot
of money from I know you're actually
working with one of my colleagues on
something around gifting so we'll tease
that so look for Hannah collaboration I
think it's a blog post coming up on
gifting but I wanted to get back to
something you said there so you've
actually seen cost decrease December 1st
and then even on the 15th they decrease
even more so starting December 15th is
when as a digital product because
e-commerce spend has dropped
dramatically once people can't get it
shipped for Christmas that's actually a
great opportunity is what you're saying
okay absolutely is yeah all the way
until the end of January gotcha I had a
little backward in my mind not having
spent myself this is why I like talking
to people like you you've worked with
250 companies you've been buying ads for
12 years I've talked to a lot of folks
over the years and I get certain
impressions in my mind and that was one
of them but it's good to know that
November's the worst December starts
improving and then huge opportunity
around New Year's it kind of makes sense
I mean you have like quarterly budgets
that run out you have monthly budgets it
was Ariel I was actually having a dinner
with him in New York recently and he saw
this one app where they would exhaust
their spend by noon they just had a
spend cap of every day we're going to
spend 10,000 or whatever it was and the
keywords would be super expensive on App
Store search ads and then by about noon
they would have maxed out all their
spending and so he was talking about
with that company they figured out okay
we don't spend until after noon and then
after that we ramp up our spend and
we'll get way better
spend so it's kind of interesting so
seasonality wise be really careful in
November and don't try and push it and
then in December expect that to recover
and then yeah yeah for subscription
products of course with different apps
it's a different story if you've got an
Ecom app it's going to be a bit
different but yeah for subscription
digital only product this is what I've
seen every single year without a doubt
it's been the same so well I think it's
a great place to wrap up seasonality and
coming out in October is perfect timing
to have discussed that get ready for
November being challenging but as we
wrap up anything else you wanted to
share I know you're ramping up at
aperture and taking on new clients so
anything you want to share there yeah
just firstly thank you so much for
having me it's been such a pleasure
talking to you about this stuff and yeah
I mean at aperture just so everyone
knows a little bit about it it's a full
service growth agency and we work with
companies that are making positive
change in the world so we're working at
the moment with apps that for example
help women and non-b people with
financial education we're working with
apps that help parents build better and
secure relationships with their children
or deal with postp part and depression
we're working with apps that help with
food waste reducing food waste not
increasing saving trees around the world
all kinds of different things like this
therapy products that have been growing
dramatically well so we love working
with any kind of products like this and
we're also growing the team so of course
if anyone's interested in working on a
selection of products that are helping
the world and you're a bit sick of
selling your soul to the dark side
sometimes then you can reach out to me
on LinkedIn or just check us out
generally but yeah thank you David yeah
awesome thanks so much for joining me
this was a fascinating conversation I
love being able to go so deep we don't
often go quite so deep on like the
techniques and tactics and this is how
you actually look at your ad spend and
stuff like that so thanks for being
willing to go super deep and nerd out on
this stuff of course I love
it thank you and have a beauti beautiful
day thanks so much for listening if you
have a minute please leave a review in
your favorite podcast player you can
also stop by chat. sub club.com to join
our private
[Music]
community